Nathan Hemesath

5413 Norse Dr Cedar Falls, IA 50613 hemesath2@gmail.com (319) 429-4274

PERSONAL STATEMENT

Through my variety of work experience, I've had the opportunity to discover where my passions lie in the workforce. I enjoy positions where I feel I can make a difference for my team and for the client. Currently, I am interested in pursuing a career where I'd also be able to use the skills I've acquired through my web developing classes. Outside of the classroom, I have also been working on teaching myself a variety of programming languages in hopes of cultivating my interest and ability to create apps. Not only do I have a passion for programming, but I also have the motivation and time management to work a full time job while simultaneously taking classes to work toward achieving my goals.

EDUCATION

Hawkeye Community College, Waterloo, IA2014-2016Bachelors in Web Programming and Development

University of Northern Iowa, Cedar Falls, IAGraduated May 2011Bachelor of Science in Criminology-Intern with the Cedar Falls Police Department

EXPERIENCE

UX/UI Web Designer, VGM Forbin,

2016-Present

I work on designing and styling the websites built through VGM Forbin and fix any styling issues or bugs that arise. I also am working with a team in Forbin to create apps for clients in the upcoming months.

Electro-Medical Patient Care Coordinator, VGM Group,

2013-2016

I work with insurance companies to help ensure electro-medical supplies is delivered to injured workers who use an array of units for their injuries, such as a TENS or an NMES unit.

Customer service and managing healthy working relationships is vital to my position.

Phlebotomist, Biolife Plasma Services, Cedar Falls, IA

2013

I serve plasma donors daily and maintain a clean, friendly environment where the donors can feel comfortable. As a plasma technician, I am responsible for setting up the medical equipment to ensure a proper, efficient donation cycle.

Warehouse worker, Target Food Distribution, Cedar Falls, IA

2011-2013

Aside from building food pallets in the distribution center, I organized my team and planned accordingly to finish daily tasks on or ahead of schedule. As an acting leader of the team, I assisted in the training of new team members when needed. Additionally, I had the opportunity to serve as part of the General Safety Team, which addressed crucial safety risk and precautions.

Receptionist, Hillcrest Park Apartments, Cedar Falls, IA

2010-2011

As evening receptionist at the apartment complex, I was responsible relaying messages between tenants and morning supervisor. I was also in charge of reporting tenants' needs regarding living conditions.

Professional Package Handler, FedEx, Waterloo, IA

2009-2011

Safety, attention to detail, and strong communication skills were essential as a package handler. I was responsible for working in a fast paced environment, while also ensuring that packages were handled with care and sorted correctly in order to serve the customers to the best of our ability.